# John Discepola

# Sales Engineer

West Deptford, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/John-Discepola/0e438a8e412446a3

A detail-oriented Technical Sales Engineer / Sales Support Engineer / Technical Writer with a wealth of experience rooted in the printing industry. Self-motivated, with an extensive background in providing the necessary engineering expertise that successfully closes sales opportunities. Strong skills in communication, leadership, teambuilding, problem solving and in creating technical documentation.

Technical skill set includes:

- Technical Writing capability
- · Barcodes / Barcode Printing
- Computer Hardware & Software
- Computer Networking
- Customer Service / Relationships
- Troubleshooting systems / applications
- Oracle / SQL database technologies
- RFI / RFP / RFQ respones / experience
- Product Demonstrations
- Training, Creation and Delivery
- Sales Presentations
- · Software Development / Scripting
- IT Infrastructure familiarity
- Testing / Quality Assurance / QA

Willing to relocate to: Pennsylvania - New Jersey - Delaware

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Sales Engineer

OKI Data Americas, Inc. - Mount Laurel, NJ - 2014 to 2015

Mt. Laurel, NJ

Oki is a global distributor of printer products, providing creative solutions and value-added service, employing 400+ in Canada, US, Mexico, and Latin America.

Sales Support Engineer, Integrations and Applications (2014 - 2015)

Supported the entire 50+person sales organization providing engineering expertise, product modifications and customized solutions that were used to increase sales in the Oki standard and OEM product lines.

- Drove RFI / RFP / RFQ process and provided responses to technical bids.
- Provided technical details required to close pre-sales and post-sales opportunities for: Advance Auto Parts, American Airlines, AutoZone, Hart Intercivic and WEPAnow. Efforts resulted in the sale of thousands of Oki printers.
- Teamed with sales group to conduct sales presentation, product demonstrations, etc.
- Resolved customer issues in hardware, software, or networking to ensure successful customer engagements.

#### Lead Software Engineer, Member Technical Staff

OKI Data Americas, Inc. - Mount Laurel, NJ - 2008 to 2014

Led a group of four Engineers programming product customizations according to customer specifications. This included software printer drivers and printer support software utilities. Distributed customizations in both the Oki standard and OEM product lines.

- Used knowledge of the entire product line: dot matrix impact printers, laser and LED non-impact printers single function and multi-function, color and mono, and point-of-sale (POS) printers to resolve customer issues.
- Directed pre-sales and post-sales efforts. Successfully completed sales opportunities including: Kodak, NEOPOST, Payless, Quest Diagnostics, Ryder, and UPS.

JOHN C. DISCEPOLA 609-221-6238 john.c.discepola@gmail.com

## Software Engineer, Member Technical Staff

OKI DATA AMERICAS, INC - Mount Laurel, NJ - 2003 to 2008

Provided programming to create software installers distributed both online and in-the-box, across the entire Oki product line.

- Collaborated with Marketing and IT departments in the design and development of the existing Oki website, particularly in the area of printer drivers and software utilities.
- Created in-house standards for ISO 9001 procedures as applied to Oki software development.
- Created in-house standards for source code control, usage and procedures utilizing Microsoft Visual Sourcesafe.
- Developed existing standards of Oki software installation. Developed software installations for all Oki products being launched during this time frame.
- Tested and debugged printer firmware and software during the development cycle, across the entire product line.

# Technical Support Engineer

OKI Data Americas, Inc. - Mount Laurel, NJ - 1987 to 2003

Resolved customer issues by providing contact via phone, email, and frequent on-site visits.

- Published end-user knowledge based articles related to the installation and use of Oki products in various environments and software applications.
- Improved Oki product line by providing feedback from customer needs and requirements.
- Provided in-house product training of Customer Support and Sales personnel.
- Tracked hardware components from a quality assurance standpoint, across entire product line.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelors in Electronics Engineering Technology**

DeVry University

#### **Master Certification**

New Jersey Institute of Technology - Mount Laurel, NJ

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/johncdiscepola

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Operating Systems / Software Tools / Computer Languages

Adobe Creative Cloud, Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign

- Platforms: Windows (Xp, Vista, 7, 8.x, 10, Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012), Linux, Mac
- Microsoft: Access, Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Other Tools: Variable Data Printing Solutions ( PlanetPress / ObjectifLune / Seagull, etc. ) EFI Fiery XF Server, Harlequin RIP, Hex Editors, Lotus Notes, NiceLabel, Norton Ghost, Salesforce CRM, VMware, WebEx, Wireshark, SaaS
- Languages: Basic, C, C++, C#, MS Visual Studio, HTML, HP PCL, PJL, Postscript, PowerShell Scripting, Visual Basic, Visual C++, Visual Studio .Net, Zebra ZPL